# Sergey Platonov

Address: Schloßstr. 33, 10459, Berlin

LinkedIn: serge-platonov-06711a136

Phone: (+49)-176-8333-26-53 Email: platonov.serge@gmail.com

Facebook: siarhei.platonau



I am a **project manager** with experience in solving **engineering problems** and the **data analysis** tasks. My academic training, the ability of **strategic planning** and strong **information and time management** prepare me to be an effective part of the company team.

## Work Experience

#### PhD Researcher-Project Manager, Pail-Drude-Institut, Berlin, 2015 - 2017

- Organizing the relocation of the physics lab consisting of more than 1000 units from Munich to Berlin and installing it on the new location.
- Technical management for choosing and ordering the new EBL system with budget of 1 million €
- Handling the measurement data (2D arrays of  $\propto 3000$  elements) including visualisation, data organizing and fitting.
- Statistical analysis of the data: FFT, wavelet transform, fractal dimension analysis.
- Preparation and publishing 3 scientific papers and more than 5 conference applications and reports.
- Improving and automatisation the measurement software and implementing new devices into the measurement framework of more than 100 devices.

#### PhD Researcher-Project Manager, Ludwig-Maximilians-Universität, Munich, 2012 - 2015

- Supervising the work of 2 master and one bachelor student.
- Budget management of around 30000 €, ordering of supplies and expensive measurement devices.
- Engineering semin conductor samples with characteristic sizes of  $100\,\mathrm{nm}$  in the clean room by optical lithography and electron-beam lithography.
- Designing the circuit boards including RF filtering and attenuation in the limited cryogenic conditions (sizes  $< 5 \times 5 \times 5$  cm).
- Electrical characterization of the samples by radio-frequency below 20 GHz and DC methods with sensitivity below 1pA at cryogenic temperatures.
- Teaching assistance at the lab-course "Thermoelectrics" for 5th-6th semester master students and exercises for the lecture "Advanced Solid State Physics" by Prof. Alex Högele.

#### Project Engineer, Institute of Radioelectronics and Engineering, Moscow, 2009 - 2012

- Budget management of 1 million rubles, ordering of supplies and measurement devices.
- Developing the simulation software for wave propagation in multilayered magnetic/acoustic structures.
- $\bullet \ \ Participation \ in \ 11 \ conferences \ and \ collaboration \ in \ the \ international \ project \ of \ OOMMF \ simulation.$
- Section secretary of  $3\ \mathrm{MIPT}$  scientific conferences.

### Education

2012-2017	Dr. rer. nat.	Ludwig-Maximilians-Universität	Cum Laude 1.6
2010-2012	M.Sc. with Honours	Moscow Institute of Physics and Technology	GPA = 4.87 out of 5
2006-2010	B.Sc. with Honours	Moscow Institute of Physics and Technology	GPA = 4.92 out of 5

# Languages

- Belarussian, Russian native language
- English full working proficiency (C1)
- German full working proficiency (C1)

## **Software**

Programming languages	Labview	Expert
	C/C++	Good
	Python	Expert
	SQL	Basic
Data analysis	Matlab	Expert
	Maple	Good
	Mathcad	Expert
	Mathematica	Good
	SPSS	Basic
Python libraries	Matplotlib	Expert
	Scipy	Expert
	Numpy	Expert
	Scikit	Good
	Pandas	Good
CAD	Solidworks	Expert
	AutoCad	Basic
	Eagle	Expert
	P-Cad	Good
Text organizing tools	Latex	Expert
	MS Office	Expert

# **Academic Achievements**

- Fellowship of Foundation of non-commercial Programs "Dynasty" for students, 2011-2012
- Winner of the research works contest on 54th MIPT scientific conference, 2011
- Candidate to Belarus team on International Physics Olimpiad (IPho) in Singapore, 2006

# Hobbies/Interests

Intellectual quizzes, hiking, badmintion, board games, data challenges on kaggle.com.